<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Pamasol Electrics Portal</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Home on Pamasol Electrics Portal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>de</language><atom:link href="https://pamasol.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Trial apprenticeship</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/trial-apprenticeship/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pamasol.github.io/en/trial-apprenticeship/index.html</guid><description>The best machines for spray cans worldwide Are you interested in the profession of an automation engineer? Go ahead, sign up for a trial apprenticeship and you&amp;rsquo;ll get a first-hand experience of the fascinating world of engineering - starting with mechanical processing and assembly, through wiring of electrical components all the way to pneumatic controls and software engineering.
The upper picture shows a Pamasol employee testing a Macromat LB20. This is a filling and sealing machine for spray cans.</description></item><item><title>Electronics project</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/nibo-burger-project/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pamasol.github.io/en/nibo-burger-project/index.html</guid><description>Programming robots for automation engineer apprentices In combination with professional school, inter-company professional trainings at Swissmechanic and practical jobs at aerosol machines for customers around the world, automation engineer apprentices at Pamasol also work on projects which focus on a certain topic.
NIBO Burger represents the electronics project of the apprenticeship. It consists of a small robot which will be assembled, soldered and programmed in the standard language C by the apprentices.</description></item><item><title>Support</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/support/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pamasol.github.io/en/support/index.html</guid><description>Getting best customer support The machine is down, red LEDs everywhere (or nowhere), operators and managers are looking at you, expecting to fix the issue in no time.
At such a moment it is important to remain calm, analyze the situation and if necessary, contact the product support or after-sales team of the machine manufacturer.
This chapter describes how to get efficient and quick support by Pamasol After-Sales.</description></item></channel></rss>