<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Automation project on Pamasol Electrics Portal</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/</link><description>Recent content in Automation project on Pamasol Electrics Portal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Definition of task</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/definition-of-task/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/definition-of-task/</guid><description>Desrciption of process flow As shown in the animation above, the Pick&amp;amp;Placer should be programmed as follows, including the visualization of the touch panel.
At first the Pick&amp;amp;Placer is retracted and the conveyor is not running The operator places a container on the conveyor at the inlet light barrier 100BG1 and presses the button Start. The container gets transported to the separator and stops there The Pick&amp;amp;Placer moves down, sucks a lid from the magazine, moves up and to the front and down again on top of the container.</description></item><item><title>Brief overview TIA V16</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/brief-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/brief-overview/</guid><description>How the development environment TIA Portal is structured To program a PLC, you need a laptop which has the PLC programming software - in technical jargon development environment - installed.
The Pick&amp;amp;Place robot is equipped with a Siemens PLC which is programmed with the development environment TIA Portal. TIA is short for «Totally Integrated Automation». More information regarding this software can be found on the Siemens website.
The video explains the user interface with the views Portal view and Project view.</description></item><item><title>Create a new project</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/create-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/create-project/</guid><description>The PLC hardware configuration as a basis As a first step a new PLC project will be created in the projec view. Afterwards you need to project the installed PLC from the control cabinet in the software. This will be done with the hardware configuration.
The Pick&amp;amp;Place robot is equipped with a SIMATIC ET200 CPU. Additionally input and ouptut modules will be added and configured.
Articel no° of the CPU for the hardware config Control CPU 1512SP F-1 PN: 6ES7512-1SK01-0AB0 Safety input ET200SP F-DI 8x 24V DC HF: 6ES7136-6BA00-0CA0 Safety output ET200SP F-DQ 8x 24V DC/0.</description></item><item><title>Set module parameters</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/set-plc-module-parameters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/set-plc-module-parameters/</guid><description>Configuring central processing unit (CPU) und IOs The modules in the device configuration are named identically as the ones in the electrical diagram. Afterwards, the address range can be assigned in the property window. Alternatively, you can open the view Device view &amp;gt; Device overview. All modules and address ranges are listed in table here.
The BaseUnits of the input and output modules come in light gray and dark gray. The light gray modules are powered with 24VDC.</description></item><item><title>Set HMI parameters</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/set-hmi-parameters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/set-hmi-parameters/</guid><description>4 inch touch panel Siemens KTP400 Comfort HMI stands for Human-Machine Interface. This is the touch panel, with which the operator controls the machine.
Add the HMI under Devices &amp;gt; Devices and networks. It is the KTP400 Comfort panel from Siemens with the type number 6AV2124-2DC01-0AX0.
Profinet stands for Process Field Network. It is a common protocol in the industry which uses TCP/IP Standards As such, the communication between PLC and HMI works similar to the internet (IP stands for Internet Protocol).</description></item><item><title>PLC simulation</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/simulation-with-plcsim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/simulation-with-plcsim/</guid><description>Emulate CPU and HMI for tests without hardware With the help of SIMATIC S7-PLCSIM the Pick&amp;amp;Place control can be simulated and tested without any hardware components added.
The video shows the simulation of the PLC and the touch panel. Emulating means recreating the functions of a computer with another device.
To be able to emulate a PLC or an HMI, you need to select the component in the Project navigator under Devices and click on the icon Start simulation in the smybol menu.</description></item><item><title>Load program</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/load-program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/load-program/</guid><description>Download program from PC to PLC and HMI To load the program from the TIA portal into the PLC. In a first step, click under devices on Devices &amp;amp; networks, where you can display the IP addresses.
CPU 1512SP F-1 PN: 192.168.10.10 Touch panel KTP400 Comfort: 192.168.10.5 In a second step you need to give the laptop, which is in the same network, a static IP address. In Windows in the adapter options choose the address 192.</description></item><item><title>Create program</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/create-program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/create-program/</guid><description>First program for Pick&amp;amp;Place robot To move the horizontal axis of the robot, creat a program in Main [OB1]. Use ladder logic with the following in- and outputs.
Description Symbolic address Absolute address Pick&amp;amp;Placer HMI Start (160SF3) PIPL_Pa_SF_Start E1.1 Pick&amp;amp;Placer extend carrier (125MB1) PIPL_MB_CarrierExtend A0.4 Pick&amp;amp;Placer retract carrier (125MB2) PIPL_MB_CarrierRetract A0.5 Pick&amp;amp;Placer HMI Stop (160SF4) PIPL_Pa_SF_Stop E1.2 PLC Clock 0.4s (2.5Hz) ME_PLC_Clock_0.4s M0.2 Pick&amp;amp;Placer HMI LED Start (160SF3) PIPL_Pa_PF_Start A1.2 Pick&amp;amp;Placer signaling column green (130PF1) PIPL_SC_Green A0.</description></item><item><title>Designing HMI</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/hmi-designing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/hmi-designing/</guid><description>Designing a link between human and machine The HMI (Human Machine Interface) 155PH1 consists of a KTP400 Comfort panel from Siemens. 400 stands for the screen size, which in this case is 4.3&amp;quot;. The resolution is 480 by 272 pixels.
For comparison: a Samsung Galaxy S22 smartphone with a 6.1&amp;quot; display has a resolution of 1080 x 2340 pixels. Regarding the design we are a bit restricted, but you can create a nice and clear design nevertheless, to facilitate the usage of the robot for the operator.</description></item><item><title>HMI alarms</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/hmi-alarms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/hmi-alarms/</guid><description>Displaying HMI messages on the touch panel An error which illuminates the red lamp exists already in Main [OB1], but we don&amp;rsquo;t have a message for this error. The lamp acts as a centralised error. It gets generated in network 7, which has the following variables.
Description Symbolic address Absolute address Pick&amp;amp;Placer Carrier extended (120BG2) PIPL_BG_CarrierExtended E0.5 Pick&amp;amp;Placer Carrier retracted (120BG1) PIPL_MB_CarrierRetracted E0.4 Pick&amp;amp;Placer Carrier extend (125MB1) PIPL_MB_CarrierExtend A0.4 Pick&amp;amp;Placer Carrier retract (125MB2) PIPL_MB_CarrierRetract A0.</description></item><item><title>Structure program</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/structure-program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pamasol.github.io/en/pick-n-place-project/structure-program/</guid><description>Dividing OB1 in separate subprogrammes The OB1, in which the program resides, can be divided into 3 FB's:
FB1 01-General FB2 02-General_Pick&amp;amp;Placer FB3 03-Cycle_Pick&amp;amp;Placer With this the programm can be divided into small subtasks, which makes the program clearer. Additionally recurring functions such as moving the axis can be programmed once and reused again and again - which corresponds to the DRY principle.
Blocktype Short Features Organization block OB Link between OS and programGraduated priorities (1 to 28)i.</description></item></channel></rss>