<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Trial apprenticeship on Pamasol Electrics Portal</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/trial-apprenticeship/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Trial apprenticeship on Pamasol Electrics Portal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>de</language><atom:link href="https://pamasol.github.io/en/trial-apprenticeship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a railway lamp</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/trial-apprenticeship/railway-light/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pamasol.github.io/en/trial-apprenticeship/railway-light/index.html</guid><description>The fusion of mechanics and electronics During your apprenticeship you will build a railway lamp with aluminum and acrylic glass parts. In addition to that, electronic parts will get soldered together following a schematic, which turns it into an electric circuit.
The railway lamp is an assembly kit issued by Swissmechanic. You can take the lamp home after the trial apprenticeship.
Additionally to the railway lamp, you&amp;rsquo;ll get an authentic insight into our daily work and all its exciting challenges.</description></item><item><title>Control cabinet plug board</title><link>https://pamasol.github.io/en/trial-apprenticeship/plugboard/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pamasol.github.io/en/trial-apprenticeship/plugboard/index.html</guid><description>Drawing and wiring schematics One of the most important tasks of an automation engineer is the planning and wiring of a control cabinet. These control cabinets can be the size of a shoebox, but also as big as four big closets put together.
The cabinets are filled with complex electronics, which are connected with wires. If one the hundreds of wires is connected incorrectly, the whole machine won&amp;rsquo;t work. In the worst case, parts could get damaged or destroyed, some of them costing as much as a car.</description></item></channel></rss>